Finding Aid for Center for Great Lakes and Aquatic Sciences (University of Michigan) records, 1945-2002.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Grants 1960-1997
  - Linda S Goad 1977-1995
    - A Great Lakes Ecology Enhancement Program for Fremont Area Teachers and Students 1994-1995 (Box 37)
    - Great Lakes Ecology Training-Grand Haven Teachers and Students 1995 (Box 37)
    - Influence of Cell Cycle and Nutrient Supply on the Susceptibility of Phytoplankton to Lipophilic Toxicants and Incorporation into the Foodweb 1991 (Box 37)
    - Influence of Lipid Composition Amplifying of Ameliorating Toxicant Effects on Phytoplankton 1992 (Box 37)
    - Synergistic Effects of Heavy Metals and Macronutrients on Toxicant Bioaccumulation and Transport 1977-1981 (Box 37)
  - David J. Jude 1977-1995
    - An Assessment of the Tributary Bedload and Suspended Sediment Loadings to the Saginaw River/Saginaw Bay Area of Concern 1989-1991 (Box 37)
    - A Descriptive Manual for the Identification of Larval Fishes of Lake Michigan and Its Drainage Basin 1980 (Box 37)
    - Ecological and Behavioral Characteristics of Three Exotic Fish Species and Their Potential Impact on Ecosystems in the Tributaries and Connecting Channels of the Great Lakes 1992-1995 (Box 37)
    - Fisheries and Benthos Monitoring in the Vicinity of the J. H. Campbell Plant 1977-1978 (Box 37)
    - Impingement and Entrainment Monitoring at the Monroe Power Plant 1981-1982 (Box 37)
    - A Survey of Zebra Mussel Veligers near the D. C. Cook Nuclear Power Plant 1990-1991 (Box 37)
  - W. Charles Kerfoot 1984-1988
    - Mutivariate Evolution 1984-1986 (Box 37)
    - Workshop: Long-Range Plan for Great Lakes Research 1986-1988 (Box 37)
  - William F. McLean 1960-1961
    - An Analysis and Evaluation of the Factors Influencing the Determination of Recent Rates of Crustal Movement in the Great Lakes Region 1960-1961 (Box 37)
  - Russell A. Moll 1978-1994
    - Assessing the Potential Contribution of Remote Sensing to USEPA Activities in the Great Lakes: A Workshop 1991-1994 (Box 37)
    - Development of a Great Lakes Database 1987 (Box 37)
    - The Relationship Between Water Quality and Water Levels in Lake Erie 1978-1979 (Box 37)
  - David K. Rea 1991-1993
    - Paleolimnology of the Laurentian Great Lakes: Early Holocene Lake Levels, Melt-Waters, and the Younger Dryas Cooling 1991-1993 (Box 37)
  - Clifford P. Rice 1982-1985
    - Environmental Assessment of the Removal of PCB-Contaminated Sediment from the South Branch of the Shiawassee River 1982-1985 (Box 37)
    - Partitioning and Cycling of Toxic Organics in the Great Lakes Ecosystem 1982-1984 (Box 37)
  - John A. Robbins undated
    - Accumulation and Fate of Potentially Hazardous Substances in Recent Sediments of Lake Huron and Saginaw Bay undated (Box 37)
  - Ronald Rossman 1980-1994
    - Analyses and Reporting of Lead and Cadmium in Green Bay Water and Particulate Matter 1990-1991 (Box 37)
    - Determination of Present and Historical Records of Contaminant Fluxes in High Sedimentation Rate Area of the Great Lakes 1982-1984 (Box 37)
    - Ecological Studies Relative to the Donald C. Cook Nuclear Plant near Bridgman, Michigan 1980-1986 (Box 38)
    - Great Lakes Trace Metal Baseline Data for Water 1981 (Box 38)
    - Impact of Zebra Mussels on Temporal Variation of Saginaw Bay Dissolved and Particulate Nutrients 1991-1994 (Box 38)
    - A Report on the Status of Lake Huron 1981-1985 (Box 38)
    - Sample Collection and On-Site Evaluation of Lakes Horicon and Tecon 1989-1991 (Box 38)
    - Scientific Study and Feasibility Study of Ground Water Contamination at Traverse City, Michigan 1983-1986 (Box 38)
  - Claire L. Schelske 1976-1982
    - Nutrient Enrichment and Eutrophication of Lake Michigan 1976-1982 (Box 38)
  - Eugene F. Stoermer 1970-1997
    - Algal Quality of Lake Michigan 1970-1973 (Box 38)
    - Anthropogenic Modification of the Silica Cycle in the Great Lakes 1982 (Box 38)
    - Guidance, Procedures, and Specifications for Processing National Water Quality Assessment Program (NAWQA) Algal Samples 1996-1997 (Box 38)
    - Paleoclimatic Implication of Late Holocene Lake Level Fluctuations in the Lake Michigan Basin 1988 (Box 38)
  - David S. White 1985-1989
    - Exposure and Biological Effects of In-Place Pollutants 1985-1989, 2 folders (Box 38)
  - Goodyear Project at Michiana, Michigan: Rock-Asphalt Mastic Revetment 1975 (Box 38)
  - U.S. Steel Project: Environmental Impact of Total Dissolved Solids in Lake Michigan 1978-1979 (Box 38)
- Topical Files 1960-2002
  - CGLAS/CILER Mini Symposium 1997 (Box 40)
  - Consortium for International Earth Science Information Network (CIESINS) 1990 (Box 40)
  - Cooperative Institute for Limnology and Ecosystem Research (CILER) 1989-1991 (Box 40)
  - Fiftieth Anniversary Celebration 1996 (Box 40)
  - Gambia Expedition
    - Correspondence and Background Information 1982-1985 (Box 40)
    - Publicity 1983-1984 (Box 40)
    - Report 1984 (Box 40)
  - Grand Haven Aquatic Research and Education Project
    - Development
      - Concept Papers 1989-1994 (Box 40)
      - Correspondence 1994-1995 (Box 40)
      - Grand Haven Aquarium/Aquatic Research and Education Planning Committee 1994-2000 (Box 40)
      - Initial Grand Haven Site Visit 1994 (Box 40)
      - Publicity 1987-1995 (Box 40)
    - Facility
      - Background Information 1993-1995 (Box 40)
      - Correspondence 1995-1996 (Box 40)
      - Facility Workshop 1996 (Box 40)
      - Lake Michigan Water Intake and Pumping Station Preliminary Design 1988 (Box 40)
      - Proposals 1994-1997 (Box 40)
  - Highland Lassie II
    - Correspondence 1963-1965 (Box 40)
    - Operating Costs 1963-1965 (Box 40)
    - Sale 1963-1967 (Box 40)
  - Inland Seas
    - General Information 1964-1977 (Box 41)
    - Inspections 1960-1971 (Box 41)
    - Operations 1962-1968 (Box 41)
    - Press 1961-1964 (Box 41)
    - Proposal 1961-1963 (Box 41)
    - Purchase and Moving 1961-1962 (Box 41)
    - Remodeling 1962 (Box 41)
    - Sale 1970-1977 (Box 41)
    - Schedules 1962-1965 (Box 41)
  - Job descriptions 1977-1999 (Box 41)
  - King/Chavez/Parks College Day Program 1989-1991 (Box 41)
  - Lake Huron Shipwreck July 25, 1992
    - General Information and Correspondence (Box 41)
    - News Coverage (Box 41)
  - Laurentian
    - Appendices I-XV 1999-2000, 16 folders
      (These numbered appendix files were gathered together in an expandable folder, but it was not clear to which document they append. They may have been prepared when Linda Goad retired as marine superintendent to inform her successor about the management of the Laurentian.)
      - Letter of Designation as an Oceanographic Research Vessel (Box 41)
      - NSF/MARAD Material Condition Review of Research Vessels, including 3.5" floppy disk with Ship Operations Manual in MS Word 2000, 1 floppy disks 3.5" (Box 41)
      - Docking arrangements/Grand Haven lease arrangement 2000 (Box 41)
      - Certificate of Documentation 2000 (Box 41)
      - Beacon Registration (Box 41)
      - Research Vessel Port Call Clearance Request 1995, 2 folders (Box 41)
      - Insurance (Box 41)
      - Release forms/Cruise report forms (Box 41)
      - Dry-dock repairs quotation 1999 (Box 41)
      - Research requests 2000 (Box 41)
      - Hoyenga, Garrit-Days at Sea (Box 41)
      - Personnel rules 2000 (Box 41)
      - Reportable Marine Casualty Form (Box 41)
      - Grant proposals (Box 41)
      - Operating budget (Box 41)
    - Bay Shipbuilding 1999 (Box 41)
    - Certificate of Documentation 1997-2001 (Box 41)
    - Dockage Agreement 2001 (Box 41)
    - Engine Replacement 1999 (Box 41)
    - General Information (Box 41)
    - Insurance 1998 (Box 41)
    - Lease 2000-2002 (Box 41)
    - Letter of Designation as an Oceanographic Research Vessel 1983, 1995-2001 (Box 41)
    - Merchant Marines Document 1987-1990 (Box 41)
    - Mooring License 1999-2000 (Box 41)
    - Shipyard 1998 (Box 41)
    - Survey Report 2000 (Box 41)
    - UNOLS Inspection 1997 (Box 41)
    - Videotape Production 1992 (Box 41)
  - Maple, 1973-1974 (Box 41)
  - Mysis
    - Architect Correspondence, Walter W. Haertel 1963-1964 (Box 41)
    - Budgets and Rates 1963-1978 (Box 41)
    - Builder Correspondence, Sturgeon Bay Shipbuilding & Dry Dock Co. 1963 (Box 41)
    - Condition Survey 1985-1988 (Box 41)
    - Construction 1962-1964 (Box 41)
    - FCC Ship Station License Renewals (Box 41)
    - Inventory and Specification 1963-1982 (Box 41)
    - National Science Foundation Negotiations and Equipment Trade 1987-1991 (Box 41)
    - Newspaper Clippings 1968-1980 (Box 41)
    - Proposal 1961 (Box 41)
    - Sale 1962-1988 (Box 41)
    - Scientist Log 1979-1982 (Box 41)
    - Ship Use 1983 (Box 41)
  - New Ship Requirements 1972-1973 (Box 42)
  - Preliminary Ship Designs 1961-1973 (Box 42)
  - Publication Lists 1989-1992 (Box 42)
  - Publicity
    - General 1962-1999, 3 folders (Box 42)
    - Institute of Science and Technology 1987-1988 (Box 42)
    - Staff Newsclippings 1974 (Box 42)
  - Shipwreck (Newell A. Eddy) Find by Laurentian, 1992-1993 (Box 42)
  - Richard L. Thibault 1964-1980 (Box 42)
  - University-National Oceanographic Laboratory System 1990 (Box 42)
- Visual Materials 1961-1996
  - Photographs
    - Big Rock Point Nuclear Plant Thermal Images 1974 (Box 42)
    - Inland Seas, 1962-1964 (Box 42)
    - Equipment Exhibit (Box 42)
    - Grand Haven Facility for Proposed Aquatic Research Center 1984-1996 (Box 42)
    - Highland Lassie II (Box 42)
    - King/Chavez/Parks College Day Program 1989 (Box 42)
    - Laurentian
      - Construction 1974 (Box 42)
      - On-Board Shots (Box 42)
    - Mysis
      - Construction 1961 (Box 42)
      - General 1963-1975 (Box 42)
      - Proposal 1961 (Box 42)
      - Trial Run 1963 (Box 42)
    - Shipwreck 1992 (Box 42)
    - Staff Display Photographs undated (Box 42)
  - Slides
    - Index (Box 42)
    - Individually-Numbered Slides
      - 1-1 to 4-193 (Box 42)
    - Submarine Star II Operations (Box 42)
    - Miscellaneous Shots (Box 42)
  - Videotapes-VHS
    - " Laurentian Lakewatch," Envirothon Cruise Documentary, 1996 (Box 42)
    - "Washington Careers Visit to the Laurentian" (Box 42)